{"tossups": [{"question": "At this battle, A.P. Hill crucially brought a group of Confederate reinforcements from Harpers Ferry, preventing the collapse of the right flank to Ambrose Burnside\u2019s troops. Early in this battle, fighting was centralized around a 30-acre cornfield owned by David Miller. Robert E. Lee retreated across the Potomac following this battle, which gave Abraham Lincoln the political capital needed to issue the Emancipation Proclamation. For the point, name this battle that occurred near Sharpsburg, Maryland, the bloodiest single-day battle of the Civil War.", "answer": "Battle of<b> Antietam</b> (accept Battle of<b> Sharpsburg</b> before mentioned)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Gilles Deleuze referred to this philosopher as a \u201csolitary thinker\u201d in his pseudo-biography<em> Expressionism</em> <em>in Philosophy</em>. This philosopher worked as a lens grinder for the astronomer Christiaan Huygens which may have led to his death by exposing him to powdered glass. One of this philosopher\u2019s books inspired Wittgenstein\u2019s system of numbering statements with its \u201cgeometric\u201d ordering. Due to his pantheistic views, this philosopher was expelled from the Amsterdam Jewish community. For the point, name this Dutch philosopher who wrote<em> Ethics</em>.", "answer": "Baruch (or Benedict) de<b> Spinoza</b> (accept Baruch (or Benedict) E<b>spinosa</b>)", "metadata": "Philosophy - Philosophy"}, {"question": "In this lake\u2019s portion of the Atlantropa project, German architect Herman S\u00a8orgel planned to refill a basin around this lake to create a shipping lane to Africa\u2019s center. Septimius Flaccus and Julius Maternus discovered this lake for the Romans. Outflow from this lake causes massive dust storms when it enters the Bod\u00b4el\u00b4e Depression. Much of this lake\u2019s water comes from the Chari River, as well as the Yobe River from Nigeria. For the point, name this lake that borders Cameroon and Niger and shrank by 95 percent between 1963 and 1998.", "answer": "Lake<b> Chad</b>", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {"question": "A majority opinion from this justice established the<em> Erie</em> doctrine which holds that state law must be applied by federal courts. This justice wrote \u201cif a government becomes a lawbreaker, it breeds contempt for law\u201d in his dissent from<em> Olmstead v. United States</em>. This man used a landmark 100-page scientifically-based legal brief compiled by Josephine Goldmark to argue for shorter labor hours for women in<em> Muller v.</em> <em>Oregon</em>. For the point, name this man, nominated in 1916 to be the first Jewish person on the Supreme Court.", "answer": "Louis<b> Brandeis</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "During Hyksos rule, this god was syncretized with Hadad to form a new chief deity. This god\u2019s temples were decorated with images of a mysterious animal called a \u201csha.\u201d At the Temple of Hibis, this god was depicted fighting Apep, the god of chaos. The defeat of this god was celebrated with a hippopotamus hunt. This god is the brother of Osiris, who he killed and dismembered. This god\u2019s conflict with his nephew may have been inspired by the invading Nubians. For the point, name this god of the desert whose myths are filled with his conflicts with his nephew, Horus.", "answer": "<b> Set</b>h", "metadata": "Mythology - Mythology"}, {"question": "Two followers of this man, Fred Dryer and William Shakespeare, were convicted in the 1922 murder of Reverend James Eason, who this man had expelled from the UNIA. Chandler Owen led a movement against this man after he met with KKK Grand Wizard Edward Young Clarke in Atlanta. This man was imprisoned for five years for mail fraud after purchasing the SS<em> Yarmouth</em> as head of the Universal Negro Improvement Association. For the point, name this Black leader who advocated for African-Americans to return to Africa on his Black Star Line.", "answer": "Marcus<b> Garvey</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "Under this leader\u2019s administration, the Bird Commission addressed forced property confiscation. MP Arthur-Joseph Lapointe helped this leader navigate the Conscription Crisis. This leader said he \u201cwould not give a five-cent piece\u201d for unemployment relief during an election loss to Richard Bedford Bennett. Governor-General Lord Byng refused to dissolve parliament at the request of this leader, instead asking Conservative Arthur Meighen to form a government. For the point, name this longest-serving Canadian Prime Minister.", "answer": "William Lyon Mackenzie<b> King</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "This politician\u2019s \u201cHands\u201d ad showed a white man crumpling a job rejection letter while a narrator insisted \u201cyou were the best qualified.\u201d An amendment named for this politician forbids the use of foreign aid funds for abortions. Michael Jordan was criticized for declining to endorse the first African-American student at Clemson, Harvey Gantt, in his race against this politician. This politician worked with Joe Biden to reform United Nations funding as head of the Senate Foreign Relations Committee. For the point, name this senator from North Carolina.", "answer": "Jesse<b> Helms</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "A terrorist from this country hired a woman who went by the name Dhanu to kill another country\u2019s prime minister with an explosive belt. The Koneswaram is a temple that has been reconstructed in this country\u2019s city of Trincomalee. Velupillai Prabhakaran headed an organization in this country that fought a 25 year civil war against a coalition that included the Indian Peace Keeping Force. That group fought against the majority Sinhalese government of this country. For the point, name this nation, the base of the Liberation Tigers of Tamil Eelam.", "answer": "Democratic Socialist Republic of<b> Sri Lanka</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "An African-American orator nicknamed \u201cBlack Harry\u201d Hosier was a popular circuit-rider during this event. The newspaper<em> Signs of the Times</em> promoted the ideas of one group from this event in the lead-up to the \u201cGreat Disappointment.\u201d A 20,000-strong camp meeting in Bourbon County, Kentucky during this event was called the Cane Ridge Revival. Followers of Baptist preacher William Miller during this event later split into various Adventist sects. For the point, name this Protestant religious revival during the early 19th century.", "answer": "<b> Second Great Awakening</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "A man of this ancestry nicknamed \u201cSilent Charlie\u201d got New York\u2019s delegation to flip from Champ Clark at the 1912 Democratic National Convention. James Kelso failed to prevent violence from breaking out against a parade of people of this ancestry in the Orange Riots. One leader of this ancestry was often depicted as a tiger by Thomas Nast. \u201cCoffin notices\u201d incriminated a secret society of people of this ancestry called the Molly Maguires. For the point, people of what ancestry led the political machine, Tammany Hall?", "answer": "<b> Irish</b>-Americans", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "The fifth prime minister of what is now this country once declared, \u201cWe are seceding from Chaos.\u201dThe first president of this country earned part of his name after going through a \u201cpoison test\u201d from the kasa tree and later faced the Simba Rebellion. The first prime minister of this nation worked with Belgian minister Walter Ganshiof and wrote an impromptu speech praising the \u201cend to the humiliating slavery\u201dthat began under Leopold II. Joseph Kasa-Vubu and Patrice Lumumba led, for the point, what country that was known as Zaire under Mobutu Sese Seko?", "answer": "<b> D</b>emocratic<b> R</b>epublic of the<b> Congo</b> (accept<b> DR(O)C</b>; accept<b> Congo-Kinshasa</b>, do not accept or prompt on \u201cRepublic of the Congo;\u201d do not accept or prompt \u201cZaire\u201d)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "Merle Evans directed his band to play this song to alert personnel of the 1944 Hartford circus fire. Auberon Waugh described this song, sung by British football fans as \u201cHere We Go,\u201d as the \u201cnational anthem of the working classes.\u201d Vladimir Horowitz wrote a difficult transcription of this piece for piano on becoming a U.S. citizen. A piccolo solo highlights the trio section of this work which was adopted as the national march of the U.S. in 1987. For the point, name this piece, often performed on July 4th, that was composed by John Philip Sousa.", "answer": "\u201cThe<b> Stars and Stripes Forever</b>\u201d", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Auditory Fine Arts"}, {"question": "Responses to this event were meant \u201cto divert your attention from the true question to be decided\u201daccording to the Tully letters. Participants in this event met at Braddock\u2019s Field after Revolutionary War officer James McFarlane was killed. William Findley tried to defuse this event by moving excise trials to local courts, and this event included an attack on John Neville\u2019s home at Bower Hill. This revolt was put down by troops led by Lighthorse Harry Lee and George Washington. For the point, name this 1791 revolt against a tax on distilled goods.", "answer": "<b> Whiskey</b> Rebellion (accept<b> Whiskey</b> Revolt or<b> Whiskey</b> Insurrection)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Claude \u00b4Erignac was killed in this region by militant Yvan Colonna. Theodor von Neuhoff was chosen to be this region\u2019s king by a man who was defeated at Ponte Novu. Independence leader\u2019s Pasquale Paoli had his memoirs recorded in James Boswell\u2019s<em> Account of</em> this region. This island\u2019s flag depicts a Moor\u2019s head wearing a white bandana. The House of Savoy consistently failed to take this island from French control despite itself controlling another island to the south. For the point, name this island where Napoleon was born, just north of Sardinia.", "answer": "<b> Corsica</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "The government of this country introduced \u201cPremium Friday\u201d in 2017, a campaign to lower work hours. In this country, students who can not find a job will often repeat a year due to the practice of \u201csimultaneous recruiting of new graduates.\u201d Steven Levitt and Stephen Dubner claim that 98% of adoptions in this country are from companies adopting their adult executives which has contributed to this country\u2019s population crisis. For the point, name this country where \u201csalarymen\u201d are often overworked, leading to a type of stress-caused death called<em> karoshi</em>.", "answer": "<b> Japan</b> (<b>Nippon</b>-koku; accept<b> Nihon</b>-koku)", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {}, {"question": "Footballer Alfredo Di St\u00b4efano was kidnapped in this country during the administration of president R\u00b4omulo Betancourt. Another president of this country supplied oil to Cuba in exchange for medics and was succeeded by a member of the MBR-200. A diplomat from this country, Juan Pablo P\u00b4erez Alfonso, created OPEC. The May, 2018 elections in this country have been contested, with Juan Guaid\u00b4o serving as the acting president. For the point, name this nation, of which the UN still recognizes Nicol\u00b4as Maduro as president.", "answer": "Bolivarian Republic of<b> Venezuela</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "In this state, Sheriff Willis McCall and his deputy probably murdered African-American defendant Sam Shepherd and almost killed Walter Irvin. Over 50 African-Americans were killed in this state\u2019s Ocoee Massacre while much of the Black community at Rosewood in this state was razed in 1923. A tribe in this state was confined to a reservation by the Treaty of Moultrie Creek in 1823. Sparking a movement to pass the 1964 Civil Rights Act, Martin Luther King was arrested in, for the point, what state\u2019s city of St. Augustine?", "answer": "<b> Florida</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "A flour merchant named Jesse Hawley advocated that the path of this project was conceived by the\u201cAuthor of Nature\u201d as it would bring more business to the Finger Lakes. The first section of this structure was a fifteen mile stretch ending in the city of Utica on the Mohawk River. The man who championed this structure was governor of New York when it was completed in 1825, and this structure was sometimes denigrated as \u201cClinton\u2019s Folly.\u201d For the point, name this structure that connects the Hudson River to a namesake Great Lake.", "answer": "<b> Erie Canal</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "These people were aided by the Duke of Buckingham during the Anglo-French War due to Cardinal Richelieu\u2019s siege of their stronghold of La Rochelle. Admiral of France, Gaspard II de Coligny, was one leader of these people who were targeted in the 1572 St. Bartholomew\u2019s Day Massacre. The Edict of Fontainebleau resumed state persecution of these people, who had earlier been granted religious freedom by Henry IV in the Edict of Nantes. For the point, name this group of John Calvin-inspired French Protestants.", "answer": "<b> Huguenots</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "This politician criticized the United Kingdom for pushing abolition in Texas in a letter written to British ambassador Richard Pakenham. This man resigned during his lame duck period after casting the most tie-breaking votes of any U.S. vice president. This man\u2019s wife, Floride, turned women against Peggy Eaton in the Petticoat Affair. This man argued in his \u201cExposition and Protest\u201d that his state was able to veto the Tariff of 1828, beginning the Nullification Crisis. For the point, name this vice president of Andrew Jackson from South Carolina.", "answer": "John C(aldwell)<b> Calhoun</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Holders of this position, led by Baldwin of Luxembourg, issued the Declaration of Rhense to separate themselves from the Pope. The King of Great Britain held this title after 1814 because of the personal union with Hanover. Ecclesiastical holders of this position included the Archbishops of Mainz and Cologne. The Golden Bull of 1356 formally assigned seven people to hold this position. For the point, name this position held by the Dukes of Saxony and Kings of Bohemia that gave them the power to choose the next Holy Roman Emperor.", "answer": "Prince-<b>elector</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}], "bonuses": []}